Guide to the H. Boone Porter Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
H. Boone Porter Papers
1940-2003
1954-1999
RG 230
Yale University Divinity School Library
35
(84 boxes)
This collection documents the work of H. Boone Porter, an important figure in the Episcopal Church during the second half of the 20th century. A graduate of Yale, Berkeley Divinity School, and General Theological Seminary, Boone was a Professor of Liturgics at General Theological Seminary from 1960 to 1970. As a member of the Standing Liturgical Commission of the Episcopal Church, he was a major architect of the 1979 Book of Common Prayer. Later he served as Executive Director of the Town and Country Church Institute (Roanridge) and editor of The Living Church from 1977 until his retirement in 1990. While in retirement Porter completed a Master's degree at the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies. He wrote several books and many articles related to liturgy and the mission of the church.
Porter, Harry Boone, 1923-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the children of H. Boone Porter, 2010
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Chronology
1923 Jan 10 Harry Boone Porter born in Louisville, KY to a prosperous family that founded the Porter Paint Company
1941 Graduated from St. Paul's School (Concord, New Hampshire)
1943-1946 Military service in Army during WWII
1947 B.A., Yale University
1947 Jun 28 Married Violet Monser
1950 Apr 12 Ordained as deacon in Episcopal Church
1950 S.T.B., Berkeley Divinity School
1950-1952 Fellow and tutor, General Theological Seminary of the Episcopal Church
1952 Apr 16 Ordained as priest in the Episcopal Church
1952 S.T.M., General Theological Seminary of the Episcopal Church
1954 D.Phil., Oxford University
1954-1960 Professor of Ecclesiastical History at Nashotah House, an Episcopal Seminary in Nashotah, Wisconsin
1960 Jul-Dec Round the world trip; HPB spent the majority of his time in rural India, Thailand, Malaya, the Philippines, Hong Kong, Taiwan, Japan, and Alaska.
1960 Author of The Day of Light: The Biblical and Liturgical Meaning of Sunday
1960-1970 Professor of Liturgics, General Theological Seminary of the Episcopal Church, NYC; established the first doctoral program in liturgical studies in the United States.
1961-1976 Member of the Standing Liturgical Commission of the Episcopal Church
1962 Author of Samuel Seabury, Bishop in a New Nation
1967 Author of Ordination Prayers of the Ancient Western Churches
1967 Editor of Prayer Book for Armed Forces
1968 Author of Growth and Life in the Local Church
1970 Received National Rural Work Award
1970-1977 Executive Director, Town and Country Church Institute, Roanridge, Kansas City, Missouri
1970-1982 Served on the General Board of Examining Chaplains
1973-1975 President, Associated Parishes for Liturgy and Mission, Inc.
1975-1982 Dean, Leadership Academy for New Directions
1977 Author of Keeping the Church Year
1977-1990 Editor of The Living Church
1979 Author of Jeremy Taylor, Liturgist (1613-1667)
1986 Appointed Honorary Canon, Cathedral of Our Merciful Saviour, Faribault, Minnesota
1986 Author of A Song of Creation
1990 Official retirement
1991 D.D. (honoris causa), General Theological Seminary of the Episcopal Church
1991 D.D. (honoris causa), Nashotah House
1993 Festschrift: Creation and Liturgy: Studies in Honor of H. Boone Porter, R. N. McMichael, ed.
1996 Master of Environmental Studies, Yale Forestry School
1997 D.D. (honoris causa), Berkeley Divinity School
1999 Jun 5 Died in Bridgeport, Connecticut
Scope and Contents
This manuscript group provides extensive documentation of the work of H. Boone Porter, an important figure in the Episcopal Church. A tribute to Porter written by Ralph N. McMichael, Jr. for the May 16, 1999 issue of The Living Church, which is reproduced below succinctly outlines the role that Porter played in his long career. All of the activities noted in McMichael's tribute are well documented in Porter's papers.
Ralph N. McMichael, Jr. wrote: "Any student of the Episcopal Church in the latter half of this century would be hard pressed not to come across the name of H. Boone Porter. In fact, his name and influence can be traced in so many places that the student should not give up the task too soon. For just when you think you have a grasp on how Boone Porter has shaped the Episcopal Church, you find out that he is doing or has done something completely different."
"Canon Porter's ministry has been, and continues to be, so rich and varied that it is hard to designate his legacy in just one or two ways. He is liturgical scholar, professor, pastor, editor and missioner. He has shaped our liturgy, our parishes, our prayer book, our publications, and our view of the ministry and mission of the church."
"A good place to begin is with the liturgy of the Episcopal Church. Urban T. Holmes once wrote that the most significant event in the education in liturgy in the Episcopal Church in this century was Boone Porter's becoming professor of liturgy at the General Theological Seminary. After having taught church history at Nashotah House, he began teaching liturgy at General in 1960. While there, he started a doctoral program in liturgy, and he supervised the graduate work of Leonel Mitchell, Thomas Talley and Marion Hatchett. All three became professors of liturgy at seminaries of the Episcopal Church. As a liturgical scholar, Canon Porter has written books on such topics as ordination rites, Sunday, Jeremy Taylor, and the liturgical seasons. However, his influence on the liturgical life of the Episcopal Church was not limited to the classroom and to publications."
"He was one of the main architects of the 1979 Book of Common Prayer. He shaped both the prayer book and the way we think about the liturgy. He served for several years on the Standing Liturgical Commission that oversaw the development of the '79 BCP. He wrote many prayers in the book, including Eucharistic Prayer A and part of B. As an active member of the Council of Associated Parishes, and a stint as its president, he shaped how we understand and live the liturgy. Again, this shaping of liturgy and life was not confined to the sanctuary. His horizons were expanding into the realm of the mission to small and rural parishes."
"Canon Porter left General in 1970 to become director of the National Town and Country Church Institute (Roanridge). In this position, he sought to deepen and expand the conversation regarding the mission of the church. He promoted the thought of Roland Allen, and he sought the development and support of local ministry, including ministry in Native American communities. He also worked on the restoration of the diaconate as a permanent order and not just a step toward priesthood. Now retired and living in Connecticut, his shaping of the church's ministry continues today with next month's Living the Covenant Conference. He has been the chief organizer of this event, which seeks to address the development of ministry within a baptismal context."
"In becoming editor of The Living Church in 1977, Canon Porter's influence expanded even more widely. As editor, he sought to inform and provoke the life of the Episcopal Church. However, he carried out this ministry not as an advocate who only offers polemics. This approach to the life of the church would be against his nature. For above all else, he is someone who lives and shares the peace of Christ. His journey has not been one of ambition and restlessness. It has been, and continues to be, one man's pilgrimage of faith. He has shaped the church because he has been shaped by Christ."
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1940-1998
II. Sermons, 1953-1999
III. Writings of HBP, 1951-1999
IV. Research Materials, 1977-1984, n.d.
V. Course-Related Materials, 1947-1996
VI. Major Organizations Served, 1954-2003
VII. Other Organizations Served, 1963-1999
VIII. Collected Materials, 1957-1995
IX. Biographical Documentation, 1958-1999
X. Audio-Visual Material, 1950s-1999
Liturgics; Porter, Harry Boone, 1923-; Episcopal Church
- Correspondence, 1940-1998; Series I
  - Personal
    - Family and friends: A-W, 1940-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Family and friends: first names only, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General
    - Adams-Axelson, 1968-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Baar-Bishop, 1953-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Blackwell-Baynton, 1965-1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bradshaw-Brown, D., 1961-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Brown, E.-Byrne, 1953-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Calivas-Campbell, L., 1969-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Campbell, Sally, 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Campbell-Smith-Cochran, 1952-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Cocolos-Cunningham, 1955-1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Danforth-Dye, 1952-1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Eilertsen-Furlow, 1953-1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gaffey-Gunn, 1952-1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Halford-Hayward, 1953-1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Heath-Israel, 1955-1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Janis-Joyner, 1943-1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Kalvelage-Kriss, 1950-1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Lacava-Lynch, 1955-1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Macauley-Myers, 1953-1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Middleton-Muson, 1952-1999 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Nargesian-O'Mara, 1943-1995 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Packner-Quinn, 1954-1999 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Rademaker-Rutledge, 1952-1998 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Said-Spofford, 1955-1998 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Starmann-Sykes, 1955-1998 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Talley-Tyler, 1955-1999 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Urban-Vogel, 1953-1998 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Wagenseil-Whitney, 1953-1998 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Williams-Zimmerman, 1956-1998 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - First names only: Al-Travis, 1952-1998 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Organizations/companies, 1979-1999 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Unidentifiable, 1954-1999 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Topical
    - Alaska trip, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Round the world trip, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      Scope and Contents
      See also the related photgraphs in Series X, box 83, folders 856 and 863. Porter noted that his 1960 trek had a major input into his thinking in revising Episcopal Church liturgy as it was eventually embodied in the Revised Book of Common Prayer. His experiences in Asia and Alaska contributed to his view that one should understand exact meaning of what was recited during worship services, and the best way to achieve that goal was to use familiar everyday language throughout the service.
    - British correspondence re. "Ordination Prayers", 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - HBP Sr. Condolences, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Seabury-Western, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - University of the West Indies, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Vestments, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Christmas Card, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Creation and Liturgy Festschrift, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Gabrielle's wedding, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Weddings, 1983-1997 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - C.S. Lewis controversy: The Lewis Legacy, 1989-1999 (Box 6, Folder 45-47)
- Sermons, 1953-1999
  - Liturgical Year
    - I Advent, 1976-1989 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - II Advent, 1976-1989 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - III Advent, 1957-1989 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - IV Advent, 1957-1989 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Christmas Eve/Day, 1958-1989 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - I Christmas, 1979-1989 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - II Christmas, 1956-1988 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Holy Name/Epiphany, 1984-1989 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Epiphany I, 1976-1990 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Confession of St. Peter, 1981-1990 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - II Epiphany, 1958-1989 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - III Epiphany, 1958-1990 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - The Presentation/Candlemas, 1975-1999 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - IV Epiphany, 1980-1990 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - V Epiphany, 1960-1988 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - VI Epiphany, 1980-1990 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - VII Epiphany, 1980-1990 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Septuagesima, 1958-1964 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Sexagesima, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Quinquagesima, 1958-1990 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Ash Wednesday, 1958-1989 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Mid-Lent sundays, 1957-1989 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - I Lent, 1958-1996 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - II Lent, 1956-1990 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - III Lent, 1953-1990 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - IV Lent/Mothering Sunday, 1958-1967 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - V Lent, 1980-1998 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Lenten Evensong, 1980-1990 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Palm Sunday, 1958-1993 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Holy Week, 1979- (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Maundy Thursday, 1975-1998 (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Good Friday, 1956-1990 (Box 9, Folder 79)
    - Easter Vigil/Day, 1958-1990 (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - Thomas Sunday, 1958-1990 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - III Easter, 1977-1990 (Box 9, Folder 82)
    - IV Easter, 1976-1990 (Box 9, Folder 83)
    - V Easter, 1977-1990 (Box 9, Folder 84)
    - Rogation Sunday, 1960-1989 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - VII Easter, 1959-1990 (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - Pentecost, 1957-1994 (Box 10, Folder 87)
    - Trinity Sunday, 1957-1990 (Box 10, Folder 88)
    - Propers 3-9, 1959-1989 (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - Propers 10-12, 1979-1992 (Box 10, Folder 90)
    - Propers 13-17, 1980-1996 (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - Propers 18-20, 1978-1989 (Box 11, Folder 92)
    - Propers 21-24, 1976-1996 (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - Propers 25-28, 1976-1989 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - Sunday before Advent/Christ the King, 1976-1989 (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - Ordinary Time: one full cycle, 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Special Feasts
    - Saints Peter and Paul, 1976-1988 (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - Transfiguration, 1978-1990 (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - All Saint's Day, 1955-1994 (Box 12, Folder 99)
    - Holy Cross, 1958-1980 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - Thanksgiving, 1961-1987 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1982 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - Special occasions
    - Weddings, 1981-1983 (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - Funerals, 1975-1989 (Box 12, Folder 104)
    - Ordinations, 1962-1967 (Box 12, Folder 105)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-1994 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Handwritten sermons, 1954-1998, no date (Box 12, Folder 107-109)
  - Hymn selections
    - Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 110)
    - St. Peter's Church, Wisconsin, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 111)
- Writings of HBP, 1951-1999; Series III
  - Books
    - The Ordination Prayers of the Ancient Western Churche s: reviews, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 112)
    - The Day of Light, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 113)
    - The Day of Light: mss., 1960 (Box 13, Folder 114)
    - The Day of Light: reviews, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 115)
    - The Day of Light (2nd ed.): mss., 1987 (Box 13, Folder 116)
    - The Day of Light (2nd ed.): correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 13, Folder 117)
    - Growth and Life in the Local Church, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 118)
    - Growth and Life in the Local Church: correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    - A Song of Creation, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 120)
  - Articles and essays
    Articles and essays by HBP are arranged by date, followed by undated articles listed by title. Sample titles only have been provided. A bibliography of articles written by HBP for The Living Church is contained in Box 13, Folder 121. This bibliography was prepared by Richard Mammana in 2009-2011.
    - Bibliography of articles written by HBP for The Living Church " 1972-1998 (Box 13, Folder 121)
    - Including: "The Liturgical Evidence Regarding the Origin of Albigensianism", 1951 (Box 13, Folder 121)
    - Including: "The Theophany Rites in the West," "Cosin's Hours of Prayer: A Liturgical Review," "Font and Sepulchre," and " Maxentius of Aquileia and the North Italian Baptismal Rites", 1952-1955 (Box 13, Folder 122)
    - Including: "The Origin of the Medieval Rite for Annointing the Sick or Dying," "The Eucharistic Piety of Justin Martyr," and "Sister Anne: Pioneer in Women's Work", 1956-1960 (Box 14, Folder 123)
    - Including: "Truman Heminway: Priest-Farmer", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 124)
    - Including: "Holy Baptism: Christ's and Ours," "Liturgy in Northern Malaya," "The Law of the Prayer Book and the Authority of Worship," "Samuel Seabury: Bishop in a New Nation," and "The Ministers of the Distribution of Holy Communion", 1961-1969 (Box 14, Folder 125)
    - Including: "The Celebration of the Eucharist," "Holy Baptism: Its Paschal and Ecumenical Setting," and "An American Assembly of Anaphoral Prayers", 1970-1981 (Box 14, Folder 126)
    - Including: "The Religious History of Waukesha County", 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 127)
    - Including: "Hispanic Influences on Worship in the English Tongue", 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 128)
    - Including "Days for Saints and Holy Events", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 129)
    - Including: "Be Present, Be Present", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - Including: "An Unexplored Territory", 1992 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - Including: "Two Visions of Nature: Coleridge and Emerson" and "The Continuing Round of Worship: The Daily Office", 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - Including: "What Can 1928 Teach Us?", 1995-1999 (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - Including: "Let the Children Sing Hosanna: The Palm Sunday Procession in the Early Middle Ages", 1999 (Box 14, Folder 134)
    - By title: A-C; including "The Blessings of Oils," " The Canonical Hours in Classical Anglicanism," "The Challenge of Roland Allen," "Christian Initiation and Liturgical Exorcism in Gaul," "Christian Worhip and the Christian Year," and "Creation, Environment, and the Small Church", no date (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - By title: D-W; including: "Draw Near with What Faith," "Jeremy Taylor: The Anglican Chrysostom," "Ministerial Priesthood and Diaconate in Holy Scripture" and "The Paschal Mystery in the Revised Services", no date (Box 15, Folder 136)
  - Reviews
    - Miscellaneous; including: "Liminal Mysteries: Some Writings by Victor Turner", 1957-1970 (Box 15, Folder 137)
  - Dissertation
    - Oxford University: "The Reform of Holy Baptism and the Other Sacraments under Charles the Great", 1954 (Box 15, Folder 137)
  - Book contributions
    - Episcopal Encyclopedia, 1994-1998 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Ordination Rites of the Ancient Churches of East and West by Paul Bradshaw, 1987-1989 (Box 15, Folder 139)
  - Correspondence with publishers
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-1999 (Box 15, Folder 140)
- Research Materials, 1977-1984, n.d.; Series IV
  - Waukesha project
    These materials relate to chapter written by HBP, called "The Religious History of Waukesha County," in From Farmland to Freeways: A History of Waukesha County, Wisconsin, edited by Ellen Langill and Jean Penn Loerke and published by the Waukesha County Historical Society in 1984.
    - Correspondence, 1979-1984 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - Drafts, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - Publicity, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - Reference lists and indices, 1980-1982 (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - "Tour of Churches", 1981 (Box 15, Folder 145)
    - Notes: Baptists, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 146)
    - Notes: Congregationalists, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 147)
    - Notes: Episcopalians, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 148)
    - Notes: Evangelicals, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 149)
    - Notes: Lutherans, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 150)
    - Notes: Methodists, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 151)
    - Notes: Presbyterians, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 152)
    - Notes: Roman Catholics, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 153)
    - Notes: Welsh, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - Racine County article, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 155)
    - Unonius materials, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 156)
    - HBP's Merton Lecture, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 157)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 158)
  - HBP's notes
    - Jeremy Taylor, no date (Box 16, Folder 159)
    - Samuel Seabury, no date (Box 16, Folder 160)
    - Miscellaneous, no date (Box 16, Folder 161-163)
  - Resource materials
    - Baptism, no date (Box 16, Folder 164)
    - Christian Initiation, no date (Box 17, Folder 165)
    - Liturgy, no date (Box 17, Folder 166-167)
    - Ordination Rites, no date (Box 17, Folder 168)
    - Rites for the Sick, no date (Box 17, Folder 169)
- Course Materials, 1947-1996; Series V
  - Courses taken
    - Berkeley Divinity School: essays and reports, 1948-1950, no date (Box 17, Folder 170-171)
    - Berkeley Divinity School: notes: Bible, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 172)
    - Berkeley Divinity School: notes: Church History I, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 173)
    - Berkeley Divinity School: notes: Systematic Theology, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 174)
    - Berkeley Divinity School: notes: Eastern Church History, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 175)
    - Berkeley Divinity School: notes: Liturgics, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 176-178)
    - Berkeley Divinity School: notes: Missions, 1947-1950 (Box 19, Folder 179)
    - Berkeley Divinity School: notes: Polity, 1947-1950 (Box 19, Folder 180)
    - Berkeley Divinity School: notes: miscellaneous, 1947-1950 (Box 19, Folder 181)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 341B: "Sociology of Leisure", 1969 (spring) (Box 19, Folder 182)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 745B: "Seminar on Society and Natural Resources", 1992 (spring) (Box 19, Folder 183-185)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 745B: "Seminar on Society and Natural Resources", 1992 (spring) (Box 20, Folder 186)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 565B: "Human Dimensions in the Conservation of Biological Diversity", 1992 (fall) (Box 20, Folder 187-190)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 562B: "Biology and Conservation of Endangered Species and Biodiversity", 1993 (spring) (Box 20, Folder 191)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 562B: "Biology and Conservation of Endangered Species and Biodiversity", 1993 (spring) (Box 21, Folder 192-193)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 752B: "The Value of Nature", 1993 (spring) (Box 21, Folder 194-196)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 752B: "The Value of Nature", 1993 (spring) (Box 22, Folder 197-198)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 600A: "Structure, Function, and Development of Vascular Plants with Special Emphasis on Trees", 1993 (fall) (Box 22, Folder 199)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 751A: "Intellectual Foundations", 1993 (fall) (Box 22, Folder 200-201)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 557B: "Forest Insects", 1994 (spring) (Box 23, Folder 202)
    - Yale Forestry School: BIO 241B: "Evolution Ecology & Behavior I", 1994 (spring) (Box 23, Folder 203-204)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 530A: "Introduction to Soil Science", 1994 (fall) (Box 23, Folder 205-206)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 721A: "Environment and the Policy Sciences", 1994 (fall) (Box 23, Folder 207)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 721A: "Environment and the Policy Sciences", 1994 (fall) (Box 24, Folder 208-209)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 510B: "Research Methods", 1995 (spring) (Box 24, Folder 210-211)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 733B, 1995 (spring) (Box 25, Folder 212)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 730A: "Agrarian Societies: Culture, Power, History, and Development", 1995 (fall) (Box 25, Folder 213-214)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 747B: "Social Theory and Environmental Change", 1996 (spring) (Box 25, Folder 215-216)
    - Yale Forestry School: FES 747B: "Social Theory and Environmental Change", 1996 (spring) (Box 26, Folder 217)
    - Yale Forestry School: resource materials, 1992-1996, no date (Box 26, Folder 218-221)
    - Yale Forestry School: extracurricular projects, 1992-1996 (Box 26, Folder 222-224)
  - Courses taught
    - Nashotah House: Liturgics I and II, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 225)
    - Nashotah House: H.T. 201: "Caroline Divines", 1994 (Box 27, Folder 226)
    - General Theological Seminary: Liturgics 20: "Christian Initiation", 1964-1970 (Box 27, Folder 227-230)